<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Scientist</title>
    <link>https://FisherKob.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Data Scientist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://FisherKob.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Virtue Signaling and Cancel Culture in Today&#39;s Society</title>
      <link>https://FisherKob.github.io/blog/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://FisherKob.github.io/blog/first/</guid>
      <description>Note: For those unfamiliar with the issue, this article involves a discussion about recent criticism of Chamath&amp;rsquo;s seemingly nonchalant stance on Chinese treatment of the Uyghurs Community. For more context, checkout: BBC&amp;rsquo;s article.
Recently, Chamath&amp;rsquo;s (CEO of Social Capital) notoriously dismissive remarks on the Uyghurs community made at All-in podcast had drawn quite a lot of mainstream media backlash which led me to ruminate on where I stand on the human rights issues and how as a society we should go about tackling this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://FisherKob.github.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://FisherKob.github.io/resume/</guid>
      <description>Nischal Subedi Data Scientist [ website ] . [ linkedin ] . [ github ] I am a data scientist with a background in credit card and real estate analytics. I have worked on projects that involved researching new algorithms and approaches to attacking tough problems, analyzing complex, label-poor datasets, building novel production ETL and ML platforms, and help to bring intelligent capabilities to fruition for users.
One of the interesting projects I have worked on recently involved an building infrastructure to constantly monitor micro-markets using live feeds.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
